<!DOCTYPE html>
<html lang="en">

<head>
	<style>
		
		body {
			margin: 20%;
background-position:center;
background-size:cover;

 

		}

		#title {
			text-align: center;
			text-shadow: 5px 5px 10px white;
			font-size: 7vh;
		}

		img {
			display: inline-block;
			width: 400px;
                  height: 400px;
                 
                  
                  
		}

		p{
			font-size: 17px;
			font-family: Gill Sans;
			color: black;
		}

		div#tribute-data {
			background-color: lavender;
			box-shadow: 20px 20px 20px gray;
			font-family: Georgia;
			padding: 25px 25px;
			margin: 11px;
			margin-top: 50px;
		}

		

		
	</style>
</head>

<body background="C:\Users\Lenovo\Pictures\flag.jpg">
	<main id="main">

		
		<h1 id="title">
			JHANSI RANI
		</h1>

		<div id="img">

	
			<center><img src="https://i.pinimg.com/originals/23/c1/46/23c146f1a587358e355c0e793fe0295f.jpg" id="image"</center>
		
			<p>
Rani Lakshmi Bai was a brave queen who fought wars with Britishers and sacrificed her life for the country in order to save Jhansi,She was a true freedom fighter during the revolt of 1857.


			</p>
		</div>

		<div id="tribute-data">

	
			<h1 class="title-JHANSI" style="color:blue;">
                   
				<center>Jhansi ki Rani</center>
			</h1>

			

<p>
				☛ Laxmi Bhai was one of the leading figures of the Indian Rebellion of 1857 and became a symbol of resistance to the British Raj for Indian nationalists.
<br><br>
				☛  Rani Lakshmibai was born on 19 November 1828 in the town of Varanasi into a Marathi Karhade Brahmin family. She was named <strong>"Manikarnika Tambe."</strong><br><br>
				☛ At the age of 14, she was married to the Maharaja of Jhansi, Gangadhar Rao in 1842.
After her marriage, she was called Laxmibai.<br><br>
				☛ Her son Damodar Rao was born in 1851. But he died after four months.
Gangadhar Rao died in 1853. Before he died, he had adopted his cousin’s son Anand Rao, who was renamed, Damodar Rao.
				<br><br> ☛ Lord Dalhousie (Born on April 22, 1812) sought to annex Jhansi when the Maharaja died applying the Doctrine of  Lapse since the king did not have any natural heir.
				<br><br> ☛ The Rani was granted an annual pension and asked to leave the fort of Jhansi.
				<br><br> ☛ The Revolt of 1857 had broken out in Meerut and the Rani was ruling over Jhansi as regent for her minor son.
 
				<br><br> ☛ British forces under the command of Sir Hugh Rose arrived at Jhansi fort with the intention of capturing it in 1858. He demanded that the city surrender to him or else it would be destroyed.
				<br><br> ☛ Rani Laxmibai refused and proclaimed, <strong>“We fight for independence. In the words of Lord Krishna, we will if we are victorious, enjoy the fruits of victory, if defeated and killed on the field of battle, we shall surely earn eternal glory and salvation.”</strong>
				<br><br> ☛ For two weeks the battle went on where the Rani led her army of men and women valiantly against the British. Despite courageous fighting, Jhansi lost the battle.<br><br>
                        ☛ The Rani, tying her infant son on her back, escaped to Kalpi on horseback.
                           Along with Tatya Tope and other rebel soldiers, the Rani captured the fort of Gwalior.<br><br>
                        ☛ Afterwards, she proceeded to Morar, Gwalior to fight the British.<br><br> 
                        ☛ Rani Laxmibai died while fighting in Gwalior on 18th June 1858, aged 23. She was dressed as a soldier when she died.<br><br> 
                       
				
			</p>
		</small>
	</main>
</body>

</html>